

Game Developer specializing in game programming, design pattern based code architectures and inmersive audio / music for games.

Fast and passionate learner, innovative and problem solver.

Work experience in mobile casual and hyper-casual games for Android/iOS, with high level of responsability and autonomy. Experienced with agile methodologies.

Passionate musician on a Jazz/Blues quintet and ambiental composing projects with FMOD.

# **Axel Castells Monliau** Game Developer and Programmer

~

(+34) 623 10 34 34



axelcastells.github.io



axelcastellsmonllau@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/axelcastells

#### Technical Skills

- Unreal Engine Blueprints
- Unity Addressables and Scriptable Objects
- Clean Coder
- Deep understanding of Git
- Proficient with Git workflows like Continuous Integration & GitFlow

# Soft Skills

- Autodidact
- Strong decision maker
- Creative problem solver
- Fast learner
- Fast and clear communicator
- Team player
- Innovative

# Experience

# **Game Programmer** Bliss Games

2020 - Now

- Fast prototyping and developing hyper-casual games for Android and iOS platforms.
- Autonomous decision-making in terms of code implementation and execution of tasks with specifics goals in mind.
- Extensive use of Unity Addressables and Asset Bundles.
- Deep learning on monetisation and IAP solutions for mobile.
- Extensive use of SQL databases to save / read game data.
- Solid use of Scriptable Objects as data repositories in substitution to conventional databases.
- Blockchain games, using SDKs such as Stardust and Venly.

#### **Game Programmer** *Labs4Reality*

2018 - 2019

- Developing AR (Augmented Reality) applications.
- Cohesive teamwork using agile methodologies.

#### **Intern Programmer** Pupgam Studios

2015 - 2015

 Working on UI programming and design on a small team using Scrum.

## Languages

English -> Advanced
Spanish -> Native
Catalan -> Native
Japanese -> Basic

#### Other Skills

- Self-managed music production.
- Modern Pianist and composer.
- Music composing with VSTs, DAWs and FMOD.
- Martial Artist (Ving Tsun Kung Fu).

## Education

Modern Piano and Harmony2020 - NowTaller de Músics(Barcelona, Spain)University Degree in Game Development2015 - 2020ENTI-UB(Barcelona, Spain)HND in Creative Media Production2013 - 2015CEV-Barcelona(Barcelona, Spain)

### Certifications

**Programming Languages:** C, C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML5.

**IDEs & Game Engines:** Visual Studio, Unity, Unreal Engine.

**DAWs & Audio Engines:** Cubase, Logic, Ableton Live, FMOD, Wwise.

**3D Modeling:** Autodesk Maya, 3D Studio Max, Blender.

Some other frameworks, libraries, languages or tools I've used in the past: SQL, SDL, SFML, OpenGL, Arduino, Processing, Reaper...